Finding Aid for the Bound Manuscripts Collection LSC.0170
UCLA Library Special Collections
Bound Manuscripts collection
7th-19th century
UCLA Library Special Collections
LSC.0170
1 unknown (698 items)
The bound manuscripts collection consists of over 700 manuscripts from the 7th to the 19th century and covers a wide variety of topics. The collection includes a papyrus fragment from the 7th century, a North French or Flemish Book of hours (late 15th or early 16th century), Persian and Arabic manuscripts, manuscript books from the 16th through 18th century, commonplace books, Friendship albums, and personal journals.
Conditions Governing Access
Open for research. All requests to access special collections materials must be made in advance using the request button located on this page.
Armenian Bible 170/466 available on microfilm with portions available on color slides. Original not available for consultation due to fragile condition.
UCLA Catalog Record ID
UCLA Catalog Record ID: 9942304033606533
Scope and Content
Collection consists of bound manuscripts of varying contents most notable for its early material which includes a papyrus fragment from the 7th century, a vellum Breviary (French, 15th century), a North French or Flemish Book of hours (late 15th or early 16th century), Persian and Arabic manuscripts, manuscript books from the 16th through 18th century, commonplace books, Friendship albums, and personal journals.
Existence and Location of Copies
Armenian Bible 170/466 available on microfilm with portions available on color slides. Original not available for consultation due to fragile condition.
Online Items Available
Portions of this collection have been digitized and are available online: Bound Manuscripts Collection (16 items).
Manuscripts.
- Bound Manuscripts
  - Waite, Arthur Edward (1857-1942). Saint-Martin the French Mystic, and the Story of Modern Martinism, London First published by Rider & Company (London, 1922)., 170/1; Holograph manuscript. 55 leaves.
  - Lucas, Jean Maximilian (1636?-1697). L'esprit de Mr. Spinosa. Bound with his La vie de feu Monsieur de Spinosa. The first biographical study of Spinoza, attributed to Lucas by Abraham Wolf., 170/2; 140pp. and 51pp.
    General note
    See also: the Spinoza Collection Catalogue, item 306.
  - [Notebook ()]. Containing notes of legal cases concerning wills and inheritance. M.B. 1725 on front cover., ca. 1720-1732; 170/3; Holograph manuscript, 222pp.
  - California League of Women Voters. Southern Section (Los Angeles). [Dues, contribution and membership book. Los Angeles, ]., 1919-1926; 170/4; Manuscript, 292pp.
    **The Department has many other manuscripts about this League.
  - Monson, Hon. Charlotte. Journal of the Hon. Charlottte Monson (1823/1825). Diaries of the author's travels in France, Italy and Switzerland., 170/5; Manuscript, 115pp.
  - Monson, William John Monson, 6th baron (1796/1862). Tour made through France, Italy and Dalmatia... in 1817. Cf. his Extracts from a Journal (London, )., 1820; 170/6; Holograph Manuscript, 227pp.
    See also: no.170/7.
  - Monson, W.J.M., 6th baron. Journal of a Tour in the Tyrol, Salzkammergut, etc., 1837; 170/7; Manuscript, 252pp.
    See also: no.170/6.
  - Aydon Castle, Northumberland, England. [Accounts] Cash books, ledgers, etc., showing disbursements and receipts., 1692-1843.; 170/8: 1-7; 7 vol.
  - Gledhill, Mrs. Andriette Leacock (Bowen) (b. 1892). Andrew Belcher Gray, 1820-1862. Genealogical chart., 170/9; Typescript, 4 leaves.
  - U.S. Department of State. Papers relating to the cession of Alaska. Enclosures no.2 and 3 to despatch no.2115 of, from the U.S. Embassy at Moscow, December 2, 1936 1856-1857.; 170/10; Typescript, copy.
  - Stephens, W.H. My diary from Sydney (1858-1859?). **The journal of an actor. Travel diary from Sydney to Samoa, Tahiti, Honolulu, San Francisco, and Panama, with observations on the country and the theatre in those various localities., Manuscript, 201pp.
  - [Single, John.] [Account Book] Rough and Ready, Nevada Company, California (). **Daily account for a blacksmith's shop in the mining town of Rough and Ready., December 29, 1861-September 17, 1873; 170/12; Manuscript, 137pp. (lacking pp.1-2).
  - Gillette and Gibson, Firm, Examiners of Titles, Los Angeles. **Continuations by Abstract and Title Insurance Company of Los Angeles (September 13, 1887; January 29, 1894)., March 6, 1884-January 29, 1894.; 170/13; 291pp.
    See also: 170/24 and 170/25.
    - Abstract of title of that certain real property in the city of Los Angeles, county of Los Angeles, state of California, bounded and described as follows: the tract of land commonly known as the "Little Plaza"
  - Catholic Church. Liturgy and ritual. [Antiphonary. Flemish 1633.]. **f. 1[r]: anno D(omi)ni 1633 ora pro me S.M.h. (i.e. Sister Maria van den Hove, sometime Director, Covent of Bethanie, Mechelen, Antwerp)., 170/14; Manuscript, on paper. 155 leaves.
  - [Franco, Niccolo?] Vita di Pietro Aretino del Berni., 1538; 170/15; Manuscript, 45 leaves.
  - Wyndham, Henry Penruddock (1736/1819). [Journals]. **A series of records of travels in Scotland, England, France, Italy and Sicily, Switzerland, and Germany., 1758/1767; 170/16; 9 vol.
    See also: 170/18.
  - Moores, Petrus. Prayer Book. Prayers in English and Latin for use in church services., 1726; 170/17; Manuscript, 165pp.
  - Wyndham, Henry Penruddock (1736-1819). A Gentleman's Tour through Monmouthshire and Wales in the Months of June and July 1774, London, 1775.; 170/18; 218pp. with interleaved Manuscript notes throughout. **The notes are copious, and presumably were used in the second edition (Salisbury 1781).
    See also: 170/16.
  - Woburn Book Society (Woburn Parish, Bedfordshire, Great Britain). Journal of the Woburn Book Society. **Includes the articles of the Society, minutes of meetings and accounts for books bought and sold., October 17, 1796-December 1, 1856; 170/19; Manuscript, 304pp.
  - Catholic Church. Liturgy and ritual. Breviary. Breviary with Cistercian calendar Italy, s. XVI². **Written in semi-gothic script. Includes circular diagram for finding the Golden numbers starting with the year 1501, with instructions in French. Cf. Ferrari., 170/20; Manuscript, on parchment. 230 leaves. Also, pp.44-45 (diagram).
  - Nicholaus of Cues. Germany, s. XV². Incipit: Pandam nunc que uobis dilectissimis. **Note of ownership of the Carthusian Monastery, Buxheim. Cf. Ferrari., 170/21; Manuscript, on vellum. 114 leaves. Also, pp.45-46 (note).
  - Augustinus, Aurelius, Saint, Bishop of Hippo. Sermones sancti Augustini ... ad fratres heremitas (Italy, s. XV med. or XV²). Cf. Ferrari., 170/22; pp.46-47.
  - Bathe, Henry de, d. 1260. The Charter of Romney-Marsh; or the Laws and Customs of Romney-Marsh. ** Copied from the printed edition (London, ) by Albert Cock while in school at Woodchurch, Kent, 1686 ca. 1831-1837.; 170/23; Manuscript, 169pp.
  - Gillette, Gibson and Wood, firm, examiners of titles, Los Angeles. ()., November 6, 1883-June 29, 1887; 170/24; Document. 81pp.
    See also: 170/13 and 170/25.
    - Abstract of title of that certain real property in the county of Los Angeles, state of California, bound and described as follows: Rancho San Jose de Buenos Ayres
  - Gillette, Gibson and Wood, firm, examiners of titles, Los Angeles. ()., October 26, 1887-August 10, 1889; 170/25; Document. 129pp.
    See also: 170/13 and 170/24.
    - Abstract of title of that certain real property in the Rancho San Jose de Buenos Ayres, county of Los Angeles, state of California, bounded and described as follows: all of said Rancho as per map appearing on page 53 of this abstract
  - Catholic Church. Liturgy and ritual. Horae beatae Mariae Virginis (use of Rome), France s. XVI ex. Cf. Ferrari., 170/26; Manuscript, on parchment, 223pp. and pp.47-48.
  - Horatius Flaccus, Quintus. Translations into English from the Odes. s. XVIII. C.L. Lewes, 29.1.06., 170/27; 15pp.
  - Bay State Copper, Silver and Gold Mining Company, San Andreas, California. Stock certificate book., 1869; 170/28
  - Powell, Paul M. Data relating to Henri II, Duke of Guise., ca. 1935; 170/29
  - Gregg, Josiah. Day Book, Pomona, California. **General expenses for a farm., 1886-1891; 170/30
  - Richards, Jarrett Thomas. Diary, Santa Barbara, California. **Record of his legal practice., 1878; 170/31
  - Burson, David S. Receipts, Pasadena, California. **Circa 350 receipts for personal bills., 1887-1905; 170/32
  - Willamette Steam Mill Lumbering and Manufacturing Company. Journals and Cash Book. **Records for offices in Los Angeles, Fullerton and Pasadena., January 2, 1888-September 30, 1897; 170/33-35
  - Milliron, Clark J. Diary, Bulacan Province, Philippine Islands. **Notes of daily activities as Internal Revenue Agent in the province of Bulacan, Luzon, Philippines., April 5, 1907-March 28, 1908; 170/36; Manuscript, 94pp.
  - [Commonplace book, English] (18th century). **Contains excerpts from various poets. Written in one hand. Ar. Cayley on last page., 170/37; Manuscript, 18pp.
  - Hansen & Solano, surveyors, Los Angeles. Field Notes. Used by the law firm of Randall & Bartlett, Los Angeles, as basic evidence in damage cases arising from the Los Angeles floods of 1934-1937., 1855-1890; 170/38: 1-7
  - Surprise Valley Mining Company General Store. Journal, Panamint City, Death Valley, California., November 4, 1874/December 31, 1874; *170/39; Manuscript, 312pp.
  - Ancient & Honorable Order of E Clampus Vitus. Pikesville, Tennessee. Sequatchee Conclave no.674. Knights of the Sun. Order of business at stated meetings [and rituals for initiation, etc.] Knoxville, Tennessee. **Written by Samuel M. McReynolds, founder of the Sequatchee Conclave., 1851; *170/40; Manuscript, 53pp.
  - Grove & Wilkinson, searchers, Los Angeles. Rancho San Pedro documents., 1805-1854; Typescript, 220pp.
  - Ellis, Arthur MacDonald (1875-1932). The Old Temple Block: Side Lights on Local History. **Copies of documents, photographs and court records relating to the Temple Block., 1855-91; 170/42; Typescript, 12pp.
  - Martyrologium Romanum. Northern Italy. (s. XV¹.), 170/43; Latin Manuscript, on vellum.
    **See Ferrari, pp.48-49.
  - Buttre, William. Subscription Book. **Contains lists of subscribers for a full length portraits of John C. Fremont and Martha Washington., 170/44; 15pp.
  - Austin, Mary (Hunter) (1868-1934). The Land of Little Rain, Boston/New York: Houghton Mifflin and Company, 1903.; 170/45; Illustrated edition. **With corrections in the author's handwriting.
  - Arabian Nights. Sinbad the Sailor. Quissat as-Sindbad al-bahri wa-l'-Hindbad al-barri. (Egypt, s. XVII). **Illustrated with 12 original coloured primitive pictures, probably dating from the 18th century., *170/46; Manuscript, 26 leaves.
  - Tasso, Torquato (1544-1595). Solymeidos Torquati Tassi Latino carmine reddita. **Latin version of part of Gerusalemne Liberara., ca. 1700; *170/47; Manuscript, 188 leaves.
  - Morris, F.W.J. Elva's Revenge: a Legendary Poem in Five Cantos with other Poems, London: Charles Fox, [With the Sequel to Letters of Eliza in Manuscript, copy written in the Year 1842]., 1834; 170/48; 123 printed pages & 35pp. Manuscript.
  - Catholic Church. Liturgy and Ritual. Breviary. Breviary with Benedictine Calendar. (Paris, s. XV² or XV ex.) **Donation inscription from the Constable de Bourbon (1490-1527) (?)., *170/49; 12 full-page miniatures of Biblical scenes.
    See also: Ferrari, pp.49-51.
  - Catholic Church. Liturgy and Ritual. Hours. Horae. Northern France (Normandy?), s. XV/XVI. ** Cf. Ferrari, pp.52-53., 170/50
  - Ashby, Samuel (fl. )/Ashby, Richard. Poems by the Ashby Family of Bungay, Suffolk.] English (ca. 1777-1792)., ca. 1790; 170/51; Manuscript.
  - Commonplace Book. English (1785-1800). **Verse and prose., 134 leaves.
  - Commonplace Book. English (ca. 1686). **Accounts kept at College; lists of books with prices paid; Hebrew lessons; directions for drawing and painting., 57pp.
  - Gottfried von Strassburg (s. XIII). Tristan und Isolt Hrsg. von H.F. Massmann. (Leipzig ). **Interleaved working copy of Karl Marold., 1843; 170/54; 490pp.
  - Handbook of Chronology. Breuis historiae chronologicae a conditu orbis descriptio. Northern France, s. XVI². **Cf. Ferrari, p.53., 170/55
  - Smith, Eliza. Floral Album [with poems addressed to Eliza Smith by her friends]. Boston and vicinity (1841-1844). **Includes original water-colours. Coloured lithographs are found throughout., 170/56; Manuscript, 44pp.
  - Dudley, Benjamin Winslow (1785-1870) Notes from Professor Dudley's lectures, Session 1840/1841]. With: Dr. Mitchell on a Physician's Shop, taken down by H.D. Henderson. Lexington, Kentucky (?)., 170/57; Manuscript, 109pp.
  - Green, James. Commonplace Book, London, **'The following poems are inscribed to Miss Anna Tull by her's very sincerely James Green.', 1812.; 170/58; Manuscript, 125pp.
  - Koran. Selections: Arabic. Mashaf. Qu'aranic selections. Maghribi script. North Africa, s. XIX. **Preserved in a leather pouch., 170/59; 198 leaves.
  - Shoobridge, Leonard Knollys Haywood. Poems. **This typescript differs both in arrangement and in choice of poems from the printed version of London 1910., ca. 1910; 170/60: 1-2; Typescript, 82pp.
  - Jesse, John Heneage (1815-1874). Commonplace Book. Eton College. **Includes excerpts from poets, as well as Eton verse. From the Manley Sims Eton Collection., October 1823-December 1824; 170/61; Manuscript, 53pp.
  - Rittenhouse, Jack DeVere (b. 1912). A Guide Book to Highway 66. Los Angeles, the Author, 1946.; 170/62; Corrected Typescript draft.
  - [Ellis, Sir Henry (1777-1869), compiler] Names of Persons entred in the Domesday Survey as holding lands in the time of King Edward the Confessor: taken in the Order of the Counties., 1821-1822; 170/63; Manuscript, 75pp.
  - Receipt Book (English 1804-1846). **A book of cookery recipes, gathered for over forty years from various persons; and medical recipes. Mrs. Wood, ... Lewisham., *170/64; Manuscript, 22 leaves.
  - Catalog of Bro Wills books sent **Manuscript, list of works of the 16-18th centuries, mainly in English and Latin. Includes literary, historical, legal, religious works, and the classics., 1728.; 170/65
  - Sharpe, John. Poems on Several Occasions. Oxford: Trinity College, **no.1 of perhaps five copies., 1790.; 170/66; Manuscript.
  - Absalom, P. Collectanea curiosa. **Chiefly concerns English history and antiquities in the 16-17th centuries. Illustrated with pen and ink drawings; alphabetical table of contents., ca. 1820; *170/67; Manuscript, 195pp.
  - Commonplace Book. English. **Extracts in several hands from various poets, including Edmund Waller and the Earl of Rochester. **Miss Whard, Welchman, Worcester 1831., ca. 1700-1825; 170/68; Manuscript, 110 leaves.
  - Felton, Miss. Verses and Riddles from 1766 to 1788. **Owned by Harriet Mary Amyand (); Anna Maria Cornewall (1835/1866); Caroline Duff Gordon (1866)., January 5, 1772; 170/69; Manuscript, ca. 200pp.
  - Collins, Wilkie (1824-1889). Letter to George S.G. Oliver. **Collins refers to his stay in Santa Barbara with Richard Henry Dana. Mounted in copy of Guilty River (London)., January 7, 1887 1886; 170/70; Manuscript, 4pp.
  - Cookbook. To preserve wett and dry sweetmeats. (English). **Cookery book., ca. 1750-1858; 170/71; Manuscript, 69pp.
  - Catholic Church. Liturgy and Ritual. Hymnary. Latin Choir-book. Spanish ] Manuscript, **Fuit exaratus calamo, ac elargº, D.F. Ioannis Romero, Ballesteros, Predicatoris, & Chori Vicarii Jubilati, anno ab incarnata, Sapientia, 1762., ***170/72; Folio. 37 leaves.
  - Ibbett, William Joseph (b. 1858). Ibbett's best (London: Chiswick Press). One of 150 copies. **Author's copy, with his signature and manuscript notes and corrections for a second edition which was never issued., 1899; 170/73
  - Coleridge, Samuel Taylor (1772-1834). Letter (copy) to Leigh Hunt (s.a.). **Also in the volume are pictures of Coleridge. Ex libris: C.K. Ogden., 170/74; 3pp.
  - Ezell, Paul H. The Aguiar Collection in the Arizona Pioneers' Historical Society. **Guide to the Aguiar Collection, which concerns the states of Occidente, Sinaloa and Sonora, and finally the government of Sinaloa, Includes letters to Lawrence Clark Powell., December 1953 May 14, 1825/October 26, 1835.; *170/75; Typescript (carbon) 80 leaves.
  - Moss, Leon. Catalogue of the Library of Leon Moss. **Moss was a Los Angeles Judge; his collection consisted mainly of Californiana., ca. 1955; *170/76; Typescript, 58pp.
  - Layne, Joseph Gregg (1885-1952). The First Census of the Los Angeles District. Southern California Historical society Quarterly; **Reprint of Layne's article, accompanied by typescript copy of the original document., September/December 1936; 170/77; 54pp. & Typescript, 47 leaves.
  - Forster, John (b. 1814). Pioneer Data from 1832 by the Memory of Don Juan Forster. **Copied from the original in the Bancroft Library. Oral History for San Diego, California., January 7, 1878; Typescript, 39 leaves.
  - Sleep, William A., Insurance Agent, Grass Valley, California. Insurance Register. A register of insurance policies issued to various persons at Grass Valley, Nevada County., ca. 1886-1898; *170/79
  - Pardo y Urbina, Manuel. Ligeros estudios hechos sobre la historia, siembra y cultivo del tagaco, Escuela Nacional de Agricultura de Mexico, San Jacinto, Mexico. **A thesis presented to the Escuela Nacional de Agricultur, Mexico., June 1, 1888; *170/80; Manuscript, 263pp.
  - Spriggs, Elizabeth Mathieu. The History of the Domestic Water Supply of Los Angeles. **Thesis presented to the Department of History, U.S.C. for M.A. Foreword by William Mulholland., 1931; 170/81; Typescript, 69pp.
  - Heraldry. Album containing Coats-of-Arms executed in water-colour and gold. Subjects include Admiral Stephen Poyntz and relations, e.g. Vice Admiral Sir Edward Brace, Ponz or Poyntz, first Earl Spencer and his wife, Margaret G. Poyntz, Henry de Massie, Llewellyn Nash. Arms from a heraldic work pasted in. Lithographic plates of university dress., *170/82; 46 leaves.
  - Clark, Leonard S. (b. 1835). Autobiographical Sketch. (Oakland, California. ). **Life of a pioneer San Francisco lawyer from 1860s-1900., May 1, 1912; 170/83; Typescript, 17pp.
  - La Vie de Jésus Christ selon les évangiles. Northern France, s. XV² or XV ex., 170/84
    **See also Ferrari, pp.53-54.
  - Rossi, Luigi (1598-1653); Carissimi, Giacomo. Madrigals and Cantatas. **Sixteen secular cantatas and madrigals; initial leaf of each song cut out., 170/85; Manuscript, 200 leaves.
  - Lewis, Sinclair (1885-1951). Ann Vickers. (New York: Doubleday, )., 1933; 170/86; Galley Proofs. 187 leaves.
  - Rimedi per il corpo umano. Italy, s. XVII. **An early Italian medical book., 170/87; Manuscript, 192 leaves.
    **See Ferrari, pp.54-55.
  - [Huber, Michel (1727-1804)]. Die Geschichte der deutschen Dichtkunst. **Anonymous Manuscript of a greatly enlarged translation of the introductions to Huber's Choix des poesies allemandes (Paris )., ca. 1768 1766; 170/88; Manuscript, 159 leaves.
  - [MacDonald, George (1824-1905).] There and Back. (London: Kegan Paul, ). **Presentation copy to the author's son; with photograph of Dr. and Mrs MacDonald and their 11 children., 1891; 170/89; 3 vol.
  - Zola, Emile (1840-1902). Le docteur Pascal. (Paris, )., January 14/May 13, 1893; 170/90; Page proofs with holograph corrections, 306pp.
  - Cooke, Rev. James. Cooke's Improved Patent Drill and Horse-Hoe. (London: S. Gornell, ) Bound with Directions for using Cooke's Patent Cultivator (London s.a.), broadside. **Includes 69 pages of manuscript in an unknown hand about farming., 1802; 170/91
  - Monica, Sister. Journal of the Sisters of Saint Joseph en route to Arizona. **Journey from Carondolet, Missouri, to St Joseph's Convent, Tucson, Arizona, 1870 April 20-May 26, 1870.; 170/92; Typescript copy, 36 leaves.
  - Cline, E.D. Daily Record of Activities, South Bend, Indiana. **Record of activites as Head of Bureau of Schoolhouse Planning, South Bend, Indiana., June 15, 1925; 170/93; Manuscript/Typescript, 121 leaves.
  - Lord, Israel Shipman Pelton. Letters. **Business letters and letters to his family; descriptive essays on Los Angeles and California, with particular reference to agriculture. Account of his first journey to California., December 1875-ca. July 31, 1876; *170/94; 1 vol., 209pp. Letter-press copy.
  - Vineyard, James R. Record and Account Book (Fort Tejon, California, ). **Vineyard was a United States Indian Agent. Also accounts of his sheep-raising activities near Bakersfield, California., ca. August 14, 1854/November 2, 1861; 170/95; Manuscript, 180pp.
  - Commonplace Book. England. **Verse and prose selections, with emphasis on the eighteenth century, in various hands., ca. 1725-1800; 170/96; Manuscript, 341pp.
  - Walpole, Horace, Earl of Orford (1717-1797). Anecdotes of Painting in England; with some Account of the Principal Artists. The Fourth Edition. (London, 1786). **Double fore-edge paintings: vol.1 (a) Cape Orford, (b) Presidio of Monterey. vol.2: (a) A mountain near the river of Monterey, (b) Monterey from the sea. vol.3: (a) Santa Barbara, (b) Point San Pedro (near San Francisco). vol.4: (a) The Mission of San Carlos (near Monterey), (b) Alcatraz Island., 170/97: 1-4; 4 vol.
  - Walpole, Horace, Earl of Orford (1717-1797). A Catalogue of Engravers... Second edition (London: Printed for J. Dodsley, ). **Double fore-edge paintings: (a) Cliff House (near San Francisco); (b) Mount Tamalpais and Red Porch., 1786; 170/98
  - Rocquet, Leopold. Metaphysicae annotata ... Andreae Blanche. (Louvain ). **33 coloured engraved diagrams in text. A student's lecture notes on astronomy at Louvain University., 1676; 170/99; Manuscript, 92 leaves.
  - Buchanan, Robert Williams (1841-1901). The Shadow of the Sword: a Romance. **Corrected by author. An epic novel of the Napoleonic wars, published in London by Bentley in 1876., 170/100; Manuscript, 226 leaves.
  - Couts, Cave Johnson (1821-1874). Diary. **A record of Cout's experiences during his last year at West Point; his services in the West, in the Mexican War, in the U.S. First Dragoons; and as military escourt for the Whipple Expedition from San Diego to the Colorado River. (Partly published.), September 1,1846-November 30, 1849; Manuscript, 167 leaves (reproduction).
  - Fowler, M.V.B. Diary. California; visits to San José; the California. Legislature in; trip from San Francisco to Panama., February 21-May 6, 1851; Manuscript, 61pp. **Daily experiences as custom inspector at San Francisco,
  - Villa, Simeon A. Flight and Wanderings of Emilio Aguinaldo: from his Abandonment of Bayamborg until his Capture in Palanan. **Account of the activities in the Philippines., 1899/1901; Typescript, 129 leaves.
  - Besant, Sir Walter (1836-1901). The Long Game. **A novelette in six chapters., 170/104; Manuscript, 66 leaves.
  - Snare, John. The History and Pedigree of the Portrait of Prince Charles (afterwards Charles I) painted by Velasquez in 1623. (Reading: John Snare, 1847). **With ephemera and manuscripts., 170/105
  - Bandar Log Press. Collection of items printed by Frank Holme. With ephemera, picture, and correspondence of Frank Holme, George Ade and others., *170/106; 3 boxes.
  - Morteira, Saul Levi (1596-1660). Sete derasiot. (Amsterdam 5404 [= 1644). **Book of sermons. Ink drawings by Samuel de Caceres, brother-in-law of Spinoza., 170/107; Manuscript, 86 leaves.
  - Braunius, Mademoiselle A.A. Cahier. [Holland? ] **Commonplace Book, mainly in Dutch, with some items in French, consisting of poems, letters and fragments., ca. 1840.; 170/108; Manuscript, 82pp.
  - Saltus, Edgar Evertson (1855-1921). The Imperial Orgy: an Account of the Tsars from the First to the Last. **First published by Boni & Liveright, New York, 1920.; *170/109; Manuscript, 207 leaves.